[Music]
welcome back to the channel today we're
gonna look at this which is
put it there so you can see it which is
dairy milk from australia
um if you look there
just there it says proudly made
in tasmania so why did i buy this well
you can't get that over here i tried a
black forest chocolate made by someone
else and it was pretty good and i was
buying some other stuff months and
months ago
to turn into various ice creams and this
flashed up in front of my eyes and i
thought you know what let's try it and
as
it
it's best before date is a few days ago
i thought let's just open up and see
what it's like
looks very plain standard and normal as
you can see
there you go look nothing interesting
going on there but the back you got all
these little lumps and bumps going on
let's see
what's inside
so far
i can't see anything
what is supposed to be
in it
it is dairy milk
chocolate with cherry flavoured jellies
and biscuit pieces
sounds good
what if we can obviously those little
round things i'm assuming are the
biscuit pieces
yep
chocolate
i don't know it's just a
remnants of the actual chocolate itself
any
oh yeah there's a
a jelly piece whoop
like um
yeah like a
hold on
like a little tiny
is it squidgy
not really it's pretty hard
[Music]
hard work eating through those
tastes nice though got a nice cherry
flavor
dairy milk chocolate outside of england
always tastes different
although
this time
this is the first australian chocolate
i've eaten
it actually tastes quite similar to uk
dairy milk which is good
and a little bit
the flavor combo
of this black forest chocolate is what
kind of got me you know a chocolate kind
of base with cherry pieces and biscuits
sounded really good so
i want to
see if we can recreate that in ice cream
form
and
i've also got
a load of
plant-based creams in the fridge that
are also going off
so
let's just throw all those in a pot and
see if we can come out with something
good shall we
so i've flashed up the pictures of the
backs of the cream so we've got a an
oatly
single cream alternative an alpro single
soy-based cream and then the elmery base
which as you know if you've seen my
other vegan stuff i absolutely adore
we're also going to use i think some
uht soy milk because it's in the
cupboard as well
i'm only going to calculate the fat and
sugar contents of these creams otherwise
i'll be going down a rabbit hole that
i'll never escape from so what we're
going to do is pop in
our soy milk into the pan and then i
think we're just going to start adding
in all our sugars we've also added some
coconut oil just to bring the fat
percentage up a bit then finally we'll
add in our cocoa powder we're going to
use guitars here i always used to
pronounce it with hards but wittards is
also something else over in england and
it turns out it's actually pronounced
guitars
once that's all nicely combined as you
can see it makes a nice thick kind of
base we're going to pour that into our
container put it in the fridge for a few
hours to chill down whilst the base is
in the fridge we're going to look at
these jellies
now i scratched my head in the
supermarkets trying to think of what to
do i could have gone down a completely
artificial route with cherry extracts or
flavorings but
what i decided to do was buy a can of
black cherries pitted black cherries
emptied the contents or the liquid into
a pan and give it a little taste it
really was a nice strong cherry flavor
you could add some cherry extract if you
wanted to
and add a little bit more sugar in there
and finally we're going to add in our
agar agar powder now this is a way to
make a nice vegan jelly again i've
checked the contents of the can make
sure that's all vegan as well the agar
agar is nice that's vegan
warm it up make sure it's all nicely
emulsified together we're going to
decant that into a little container and
then fill in our molds this is actually
a coffee bean mold but you know the size
was about right
fill it all up and leave it there make a
right little mess look and leave it
there just to
thicken up a little bit maybe gel over
put the rest in that little container
once you can move it put it in the
fridge
if you randomly decided to use all these
ingredients that i have here you're
gonna find that the base is quite thick
straight at the fridge so get your whisk
out and get it really nice and agitated
loosen that back up before you put it in
your ice cream machine
once it's ready we're going to remove it
and put it in a machine and churn it as
normal
now whilst your ice cream is churning
we're gonna take our favorite vegan
biscuits i mean i'm not vegan but
because i make a few vegan videos and a
few vegan ice creams i've found a pack
of these in the supermarket these are in
the free from areas and these are from
sainsbury's but
just checking your
supermarkets for a vegan biscuit it's
kind of like shortbread it's sold as
shortbread it's not as good
but it'll do the job
chop them up into nice little pieces
just put them aside and then we're going
to take our jelly out the fridge they
pop them out of the mold let they come
out really nice and easy and then put
them in another container put them aside
and then
once your ice cream is churned take it
out and start loading up your tub
here we're just going to start layering
in the little cherry jelly pieces the
biscuits and the ice cream this ice
cream's got really nice texture really
really nice texture once your tub's
filled put it in the freezer as normal
it's going to take about three or four
hours to harden up
[Music]
just got the ice cream out freezer gonna
get some dished up and see how this
turned out
[Music]
okay the texture
scoot really well really really well
smells good
it smells nice and chocolatey you can
see the bits of biscuit in there you can
also see the little cherry
jellies let's uh
let's dig in see how this little puppy
tastes
i'm not eating puppies it's just ice
cream
[Music]
damn
that's good
that's really good
super smooth texture kind of little
fudginess but not too bad the cherry
jellies come through nice strong cherry
flavor i don't know what the cherries
are like in the shops near you but these
are just waitrose own
just black cherries to count the juice
off use that you could boost the flavor
of the cherry if you want you know if
you can buy cherry juice in the shops
now you just use that instead you could
even just use water and cherry extract
and some red food coloring if you want
to but
this was a bit of a catch-all really
like i said
just to get rid of some of these
ingredients left over in
the fridge and you know what
i mean
i wouldn't make it like this normally
because it's pretty expensive to buy
these three and
throw them in a pot together and hope
for the best but
it turned out really really nice really
nice the texture is great i'll just
leave that there the texture is great
flavor combo's nice i was trying to find
a dairy milk vegan
milk chocolate but the one they brought
out over here is got little bits of
almond in it which kind of i'm not sure
would have worked in here but who knows
anyway this was a bit of a a random
test just to see if i could make a vegan
version of this and
turns out you can so
if you want to have a go at this you
don't have to use all this if you've got
your favorite vegan base go for it
soy products help a lot actually in
vegan ice cream but if you can't eat soy
then there are lots of other
alternatives out there so
give those a try and don't forget to
like and subscribe and we'll see you
next week
you